A Guide to the Smith-Digges Papers, 1789-1843
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
Smith-Digges Papers 1789-1843
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 1931.7
2 volumes and 18 items.
Papers of Dr. Augustine Smith (post 1769-1805) of Yorktown, Virginia, a friend of Thomas Nelson, and of his daughter, Lucy Calthorpe Smith, who married Ralph Wormeley Digges.
Smith, Augustine.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 1931.
Alternative Form Available
Library has a microfilm copy (M-121) of collection.
Scope and Content
Included are Dr., Smith's letterbook, 1789-1791, containing copies of letters to friends and business associates in Edinburgh and London, as well as miscellaneous verses and essays, many in a different hand; letter, 1835 April 10, Susanna Nelson Page to Lucy Calthorpe Smith Digges, giving a biography of Lucy Grymes Nelson (1743-1830); "My Table and its History," a memorial to Lucy Grymes Nelson; poems attributed to Elizabeth Frances Mann Digges Pendleton, and one by Augustine Smith; and miscellaneous loose advertisements, essays, bills, and obituaries for Thomas Nelson, Dudley Digges, Mary Berkeley Minor and Matthew Pope. Second volume is a memorandum book of notes about ministers and sermons.
Arrangement
Individual items arranged chronologically.
Index Terms
Persons:
Minor, John,1761-1821.; Minor, Mary Berkeley,1760-1788.; Nelson, Hugh.; Nelson, Lucy Grymes, 1743-1830.; Pope, Matthew,d. 1792.; Smith, Alice Grymes Page,1775-1846.; Nelson, Thomas,1716-1782.
Contents List
- Smith-Digges Papers
  - Assorted Papers, 1789-1837; Folder 1 of 3
    - "Valuable Farm for Sale" in Caroline County, 1833 Mar 11.
      Signed by Edmund Pendleton.
    - Letter., 1835 Apr 10.; 3 pages.
      Rug Swamp, Hanover County, [Susanna Nelson Page] to Mrs. Ralph W. Digges, Locust Lodge, Louisa County. Contains a biographical sketch of Lucy Grymes Nelson.
    - "The Christian Friend's Farewell"., 1835 Apr 11.
      Poem by Sally N. Berkeley for Lucy [Digges].
    - Receipted account of R. W. Digges with Mansion House, Mobile., 1835 Jul 27.
    - Obituary for Dudley Digges, Jr., (1765-1839)., [1839] Apr.
    - Poem for Mrs. Caroline Anderson in Louisville, Kentucky.
    - Essay on the Tower of London.
    - "The Graves of the Innocents"., N.D.
    - Poem., N.D.
    - "The Auction"., N.D.
    - Poems "To My Child in Heaven" and "The Violet."
    - "Integrity"., N.D.
    - "The Early Called or the Victims of Cholera"., N.D.
    - Memorandum.
    - Sketch of an animal., N.D.
    - Picture of a still., N.D.
  - "My Table and its History"., Post 1843.; Folder 2 of 3; 1 volume (30 pp.)
    A memorial to Lucy Grymes probably written by Mrs. Ralph Wormeley Digges.
  - Letter Book of Dr. Augustine Smith., 1789-1791.; Folder 3 of 3